Guide to the Sallie Bingham Papers, 1900-2023 and undated RL.00112
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2000-0364), 1991-2000, 2 boxes
  Addition (2000-0364) (400 items, .80 linear feet, dated 1991-2000) provides further evidence of Bingham's career as a writer. Materials include published volumes of her writing; correspondence; drafts of short stories and poems; journals; and two audio cassette tapes by an astrologer/tarot reader. There is no container list for this accession.
  - The Big Bed first draft, 9/14/2000 (Box 1)
  - The Laguna Master first draft, 3/2000 (Box 1)
  - Poems: First Drafts, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Radcliffe College, Class of 1958, Fortieth Reunion Report, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Royalty Statement, 2000 (Box 1)
  - The Mouse Family, 5/2000 (Box 1)
  - Canyon de Chelly, 5/2000 (Box 1)
  - Letters to save, 2000 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Proposal: Los Luceros, 4/2000 (Box 1)
  - Mustang Sally (script) by Chris Iovenko (Box 1)
  - Poems (Box 1)
- Accession (2001-0137), 1988-2001, 2 boxes
  Addition (2001-0137) (100 items, .6 linear feet; dated 1988-2001 and n.d.) contains drafts of essays, short stories, and a play; correspondence received; clippings; and astrological information. In addition, there are 1 black-and-white and 112 color (90 are panoramic) photographs; 2 contact sheets; 2 rolls of color film; 5 audio cassettes; and one piece of embroidery. There is no container list for this accession.
  - Yoga essay (Box 1)
  - Dancing Man (Box 1)
  - The Splinter first and second drafts, June 2000 (Box 1)
  - Figs, October 1999 (Box 1)
  - Rat November 2000 (Box 1)
  - Porn (Box 1)
  - How the South Won, March 2000 (Box 1)
  - Hope Springs corrected draft, Act One, February 2001 (Box 1)
  - Drafts (Box 1)
  - Texas Tech University Press, February 2001 (Box 1)
  - Flight (Box 1)
  - What Men Don't Say (Box 1)
  - Workshop, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Po Mo Fish Story, August 1999 (Box 1)
  - Apricots (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - cards, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Posters, paper clippings (Box 1)
  - Astrology (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Chaco Canyon, November, 2000 (Box 1)
  - 5 audio cassette tapes (Box 2)
  - 2 rolls APS film (Box 2)
  - Embroidery made by Sallie Bingham as a child (Box 2)
  - Panoramic photographs and contact sheets (Box 2)
- Accession (2002-0210), 2000-2002, 1 boxes
  Addition (2002-0210) (375 items, .6 linear feet; dated 2000-2002) contains primarily personal and professional correspondence (2001-2002) and writings (2000-2002), which include drafts of Bingham's collection of short stories, Transgressions; manuscripts of poems, including the compilation The Hub of the Miracle and a typescript of novel, Nick of Time. Also includes 26 color photographs. Unprocessed addition.
  - 10 color photographs from "The Top Hat Ball Winter Showcase," 2001 (Box 1)
  - Loose materials (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 6 color photographs (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - "Nick of Time" (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Poems (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - The Hub of the Miracle (Box 1)
  - Poems (Box 1)
  - Poems to submit, 6/16/2000 (Box 1)
  - The Hub of the Miracle 1st draft, 1/2000 (Box 1)
  - Loose materials (Box 1)
  - Sarah's letters, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Home/studio (Box 1)
  - Writings (Box 1)
  - First draft for 2002 collection, Transgressions (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
- Accessions (2002-0262), (2003-0002), and (2003-0003), 1 boxes
  Addition (2002-0262) (4 items, .10 lin. ft.; dated 2002) contains corrected rough drafts of Bingham's short stories Venus, Goddess of Love and Money, The Cuckoo, He's a Pretty Bird, He Sings as He Flies, and Roquefixade. This accession is unprocessed.
  Addition (2003-0002) (3 items, .10 lin. ft.; dated 2000-2001) comprises drafts of two short stories and notes for a third story, Transgressions. The short story drafts contain Bingham's edits. This accession is unprocessed.
  Addition (2003-0003) (30 items, .10 lin. ft.; n.d.) contains manuscripts for 30 poetry pieces. Several pieces have corrections and directions for the typesetter. This accession is unprocessed.
  - Short stories (2002-0262) (Box Acc. 02-0262, 03-0002, 03-0003: Box 1)
  - Short stories (2003-0002) (Box Acc. 02-0262, 03-0002, 03-0003: Box 1)
  - Poetry (2003-0003) (Box Acc. 02-0262, 03-0002, 03-0003: Box 1)
- Accessions (2003-0024) and (2003-0067), 1970s-2002, 2 boxes
  Additions (2003-0024) and (2003-0067) (375 items; .8 lin. ft.; dated 1970s-2002 and n.d.) comprises manuscripts of Bingham's short fiction, personal and professional correspondence, notes, and subject files. This accession is unprocessed.
  - Portrait of Sallie Bingham (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Mary Oliver (Box 1)
  - Mann essay for the Salt Journal (Box 1)
  - The Princess Discontent (Box 1)
  - Greensboro Review (Box 1)
  - Old stories (Box 1)
  - Writing the personal essay (Box 1)
  - Millicent Rogers (Box 1)
  - Helen Brann - 2002 (Box 1)
  - Ann Cooper (Box 1)
  - Notebook (Box 1)
  - Flood Pleiades Production, October 1996 (Box 1)
  - Play reviews, etc. (Box 1)
  - Ideas for plays (Box 1)
  - "Trespasses" (Box 1)
  - Women's Project reading, 6/2002 (Box 1)
  - Carrington (Box 1)
  - Marian Coffin (Box 1)
  - Stories (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Stories (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Writings (Box 2)
  - Plays by Jonathan Bingham (Box 2)
  - Letters to keep, 2002 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Writer's Digest (Box 2)
  - Published stories (Box 2)
  - Family letters (2 folders) (Box 2 (2003-0126) RESTRICTED)
  - Loose materials (Box 2 (2003-0126) RESTRICTED)
  - Notebook (Box 2 (2003-0126) RESTRICTED)
  - ForeWord Award (Box 2 (2003-0126) RESTRICTED)
  - Mesa Verde (Box 2 (2003-0126) RESTRICTED)
  - Ad Hoc Writing class (Box 2 (2003-0126) RESTRICTED)
  - Treason (2 folders) (Box 2 (2003-0126) RESTRICTED)
  - Articles (Box 2 (2003-0126) RESTRICTED)
- Accessions (2003-0087) and (2003-0097)--RESTRICTED, 8 boxes
  Additions (2003-0087) and (2003-0097) (2800 items, 4.4 lin. ft.; dated 1920s-2003 and n.d.) consists largely of manuscripts and typescripts of Bingham's poetry, prose, and plays ([1970s]-2003). Also includes personal diaries, 1992-2003; photographs of Bingham and her friends/family; clippings of articles and reviews; an appraisal report of Wolf Pen Mill Farm (property that contains Sallie's artist retreat); and a small amount of printed material and correspondence.
  Patrons must request permission from the donor for access to personal information.
  - Contents of Box 1: (Box 1)
    - Plays, poems, and short stories, 1996-2003 and undated (Box 1)
      Includes drafts, typescripts and manuscripts, and a self-published chapbook of poetry.
  - Contents of Box 2: (Box 2)
    - Plays and poems, 2000-2003 and undated (Box 2)
    - Appraisal report of Wolf Pen Mill Farm (property that contains Bingham's artist retreat) by Chapman and Bell, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Diaries, 2000-2002 (Box 2)
  - Contents of Box 3: (Box 3)
    - Diaries, including poetry diaries, 1995-2003 (Box 3)
  - Contents of Box 4: (Box 4)
    - Diaries, including poetry diaries, 2000-2002 (Box 4)
    - HD Microfilms from Beinecke Library at Yale (Box 4)
    - Bottle with wedding invitation (Bingham's son's wedding) (Box 4)
  - Contents of Box 5: (Box 5)
    - Blacks in Lexington Oral History Project, University of Kentucky Library (3 audio tapes) (Box 5)
    - Diary, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Plays, 1980s (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous notes, workshop materials, and correspondence (Box 5)
    - Clippings and photocopies of articles and reviews related to Bingham and her works (Box 5)
  - Contents of Box 6: (Box 6)
    - Photos of Sallie Bingham and family, 1920s- 1970s (Box 6)
    - Stories (drafts, typescripts, published in the Louisville Review) (Box 6)
  - Contents of Box 7: (Box 7)
    - Poems, stories, and plays, 1990-1997 and undated (Box 7)
      Includes notes, drafts, manuscripts and typescripts.
    - Photos of Sallie Bingham, early 1970s (Box 7)
  - Contents of Box 8: (Box 8)
    - Story, 1990s (Box 8)
    - Bound Piggyback script, 1970s (Box 8)
    - Bound teleplay, The Wall Between, 1970s (Box 8)
- Accession (2003-0126), 1949-2003, 1 boxes
  Addition (2003-0126) (80 items, .2 lin. ft.; dated 1949-2003 and n.d.) consists of family letters, 1949-[1960s]; two versions of Bingham's play, Treason; short story drafts; and other miscellaneous items. Unprocessed addition.
  Access is restricted. Patrons must obtain permission from the donor to use these materials.
  - Letters to save (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Notebook (Box 2)
  - Transgressions - royalties (Box 2)
  - What Mom Didn't Say (Box 2)
  - HD photo (Box 2)
  - World War I and II postcards (Box 2)
  - Throwaway, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Children of Cronus (Box 2)
  - Fragments (Box 2)
  - Typescripts (Box 2)
  - Family Jewels, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Whole, May 2001 (Box 2)
  - A Woman's Land (Box 2)
  - Yoga in the Seventies (Box 2)
  - Sweet peas (Box 2)
  - Tree of Life first draft (Box 2)
  - Poems (Box 2)
  - Portraits of Sallie Bingham (Box 2)
- Accessions (2003-0207) and (2003-0210), 1916-2003, 1 boxes
  Additions (2003-0207) and (2003-0210) (275 items, .5 lin. ft.; dated 1916-2003 and n.d.) consist largely of miscellaneous writings, including notes and drafts of poems, plays, and stories. Also includes personal correspondence from friends and family (1968-2003); a folder of World War I and II-era postcards; and photographs of Bingham and other subjects. Unprocessed additions.
  - Writings, correspondence, notes, and other files, 1916-2003 (Box Acc. 03/207, 03/210: Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Written permission from the donor, Sallie Bingham, is necessary before accessing the following: diaries, notebooks, correspondence, photographs, legal and financial papers, and files associated with the following: Kentucky Foundation for Women, The American Voice, and Santa Fe Stages. Not covered by this restriction: writings, speeches, clippings, subject files, audiovisual materials.
- Accession (2004-0067), 2002-2004, 2 boxes
  Addition (2004-0067) (240 items, 1.2 lin. ft.; dated 2002-2004) contains primarily Bingham's diaries and other writings, including plays, poems, short stories, essays, and book proposals, in draft and published formats. Also includes correspondence, files related to Bingham's son, Will Iovenko, her public appearances, and Wolf Pen Farm. Addition is closed to researchers.
  Access is restricted. Patrons must obtain permission from donor to use these materials.
  - Intro: Dance of the Muses, 1st draft (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Julie Miles of Women's Project, 1977-2003 (Box 1)
  - Photograph of Ann Cooper (Box 1)
  - Letters to save (Box 1)
  - Throwaway (Box 1)
  - Dancing as Writing, Writing as Dancing (Box 1)
  - For Contemporary Authors (Box 1)
  - Poems, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Stories to work on (Box 1)
  - Letters to save, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Draft: Book proposal, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Will Iovenko (Box 1)
  - Virgin Hair (Box 1)
  - The Dance of the Muses (Box 1)
  - Letters to save (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia (Box 1)
  - Wolf Pen Farm, 2004 (Box 1)
  - South by Southwest Collection (Box 1)
  - Proposal: Hotel Biron (Box 1)
  - Hotel Biron (Box 1)
  - Notes for Harvard Club Fall, November 2003 (Box 1)
  - 4 diaries, 2000-2004 (Box 1)
  - 9 diaries (Box 2)
  - Southwest Review Vol. 88, nos. 2 & 3 (Box 2)
  - Book proposal: Dance of the Muses (Box 2)
  - Newspaper article on Bingham family, 1988 (Box 2)
  - St. John's Lecture (Box 2)
- Accession (2005-0010), 1991-1992, 1 boxes
  - Scrapbook of Kentucky Foundation for Women Founder's Day, 1991-1992 (Box Acc. 05/0010: Box 1)
    Written permission from the donor, Sallie Bingham, is necessary before accessing files related to the Kentucky Foundation for Women.
- Accession (2005-0084), 1959-2003, 3 Boxes (850 items, 1.8 lin. ft.
  - Childhood notebook, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Photography of school play production of Midsummer Night's Dream, 1948 (Box 1)
  - First draft, Hotel des Dames (Box 1)
  - The Harvard Advocate, November, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Poems for Ned, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Dancing Man (Box 1)
  - Letters, 2004/2005 (Box 1)
  - Untitled Novel, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Drafts (Box 1)
  - L'Hotel des Dames, uncorrected (Box 1)
  - "The Ones Who are Left Out" (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Writings (Box 1)
  - Old House - drafts (Box 1)
  - Draft Ch. 1 and 2 - L'Hotel (Box 1)
  - Chapter three: 2nd draft, This Old House (Box 1)
  - Dance of the Muses 2/28/2004 (Box 1)
  - Letters to keep, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Letters to save, 2003 (Box 1)
  - 6 photographs of the Truchas Community Center (Box 1)
  - An Instrument Ordained (Box 1)
  - Margaret Hassan (Box 1)
  - Treason reading, 5/2005 (Box 1)
  - Bay Street Theatre, Sage Harbor (Box 1)
  - Treason: Theatre (Box 1)
  - Treason (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Throwaway by Bingham, draft (Box 2)
  - Throwaway spiral bound script (Box 2)
  - Diary, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Sweet Peas by Bingham - draft (Box 2)
  - Personal correspondence (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Six notebooks, 2004-2005 (Box 3)
- Accession (2006-0004), 2005
  Access restricted. Patrons must obtain permission from donor to use these materials.
  - Diary, November-December 2005 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Rough draft, Essay on Jane Austen, undated (Box 1)
  - Third draft, Book Proposal, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2005 (Box 1)
  - The Millstone, Spring 2005, Kentucky Old Mill Association (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 1)
- Accession (2006-0060), 1998-2005
  - Outline Part Two (Box 1)
  - Bowling Green, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Proposal first draft (Box 1)
  - Part II, Chapter two (Box 1)
  - Part two (Box 1)
  - Prologue: This Old House (Box 1)
  - Outline - Part One (Box 1)
  - "The Man who Loved Women" (Box 1)
  - Chapter Ten, handwritten draft (Box 1)
  - Letters to keep (Box 1)
  - Cory's Feast review (Box 1)
  - Clippings and correspondence (Box 1)
  - An Old House in Paris manuscript (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Appointment book (Box 2)
  - The Old House in Paris, first draft, 2002-2005 (Box 2)
  - The Kentucky Review, Vol. 8 no. 3, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Southwest Review, Vol. 84, no. 4, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Passages North, Vol. 16, no. 2, Winter 1994 (Box 2)
  - The American Voice, no. 29, 1992 and no. 41, 1996 (Box 2)
  - 5 diaries (Box 2)
  - Mary Bingham, A Rotary Toast, April 18, 1995 (VHS) (Box 3)
  - 2 New Films from Apparatus: He Was Once by Mary Hestand and La Davina by Brooke Dammkoehler (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Tommy's: A Film by Barry Ellsworth (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Wolf Pen Branch Mill Farm Video (VHS) (Box 3)
- Accession (2006-0106), 2004-2006
  - The Hub of the Miracle (Box 1)
  - Cory'sFeast (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Sunstone Press (Box 1)
  - Agent (Box 1)
  - Hub of the Miracle final (Box 1)
  - The Hub of the Miracle, final draft (Box 1)
  - Barry Bingham Jr (Box 1)
  - Submissions (Box 1)
  - Work (Box 1)
  - Treason (Box 1)
  - Hub of the Miracle, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Cory's Feast - Final (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Treason (Box 1)
  - Letters, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Treason, bound script (Box 1)
  - Editors' letters (Box 1)
  - Sweetbriar (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Throwaway, bound script (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
- Accession (2007-0034), 2006-2007
  - Letters, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  - 4 notebooks (Box 1)
- Accession (2008-0032), 1983-2008
  - Art and Feminism (Box 1)
  - Coming to Terms, draft (Box 1)
  - Book notes (Box 1)
  - Treason, notes (Box 1)
  - Treason, journal, rough draft (Box 1)
  - Provence/Pound (Box 1)
  - Pound essay, 10/2006 (Box 1)
  - Ezra Pound (Box 1)
  - A Light from Eleusis (Box 1)
  - The Willingness to Undo Knots: A Collection of Poems (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Treason - most recent (Box 1)
  - Curious Castle, short version (Box 1)
  - The Old Lady (Box 1)
  - Letters, 2007-2008 (Box 1)
- Accession (2008-0044), 1980-2008
  - Four notebooks (Box 1)
  - Drug Policy Reform (Box 1)
  - Art of Feminism (Box 1)
  - River Fields (Box 1)
  - Charitable Donations, 1/2007 (Box 1)
  - Short story drafts, 2003-2008 (Box 1)
  - Early draft, Old Lady, 1980s (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Letters re: Pound (Box 1)
  - H2 to Pound, 1920s (Box 1)
  - Willingness to Undo Knots (Box 1)
  - Red Car (Box 1)
  - Red Car, proofs (Box 1)
  - Sarabande books catalog, 2007-2008 (Box 1)
  - A Dangerous Personality, latest draft, 6/7/2007 (Box 2)
  - Mahahua letter (Box 2)
  - HPB Act Two (Box 2)
  - Red Car, draft (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Ezra Iovenko (Box 2)
  - A Concert in memory of Barry Bingham Jr., September 23, 2006, CD (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
  - A Dangerous Personality, revised 5/2007 (Box 2)
  - The Man who Loved Women (Box 2)
  - HPB notes, Act 2 (Box 2)
  - Writings (Box 2)
  - Kentucky Foundation for Women grants (Box 2)
  - A Rose for Madame Blavatsky (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Clipping from Santa Fe Reporter, September 26 - October 2, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Photographs (Box 2)
- Accession (2009-0001), 1990-2008
  - Women Moving Millions (Box 1)
  - St. Bee's talk, October 2008 (Box 1)
  - Kentucky-NC-NY, October 2008 (Box 1)
  - Snake Goddess Talk, October 2008 (Box 1)
  - River Fields (Box 1)
  - KY Play Anthology, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Clippings and Notebook (Box 1)
  - Journal (Box 1)
  - A Dangerous Personality, Revised Rehearsal Script, April/May 2008 (Box 1)
  - Five Poems (Box 1)
  - Letters (Box 1)
  - The World is Our Oyster, Writing Women, July 22, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Published short stories (Box 1)
  - Thunder thy Clarion (Box 1)
  - Best Romance, New Mexico Book Awards trophy, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 2-3)
- Accession (2009-0149) 2001-2009
  - Red Car, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Sarabande books (Box 1)
  - Sarabande agreement, 2003-2007 (Box 1)
  - Transgressions contract, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Poetry catalog, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Nick of Time royalty (Box 1)
  - Red Car reviews (Box 1)
  - Reviews, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - Ms. cover, June 1986 (Box 1)
  - If In Darkness drafts (Box 1)
  - The Fiest (Box 1)
  - Seagull, Heaven, 2009 (Box 1)
  - How the South Won (Box 1)
  - New fiction, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - Writing, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - Becoming first rough draft (Box 1)
  - Notes, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Submissions, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - Drafts, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Letters, 2008-2009 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Business letters, 2008-2009 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Guggenheim recommendation, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Civil War prison article (Box 1)
  - Louisville Collegiate School (Box 1)
  - Robin Romm's class, 2008 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - NM Revocable Trust (amended), 2009 (Box 1)
  - Photographs and albums, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Photographs and letters, undated (Box 2)
  - Diary, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Wolf Branch Mill (Box 2)
  - Hopscotch House, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Bingham Poetry Room (Box 2)
  - What does it mean to breath? [sic] (Box 2)
  - Founders' Day, Sept. 2006 (Box 2)
  - Walkbook, June 2007 (Box 2)
- Accession (2009-0183), 1800-2009; 2 boxes
  Addition (2009-0183) (900 items; 1.2 lin. ft.; dated 1960s-2000s) includes manuscripts of essays and short stories; drafts of plays and accompanying production materials; research files and correspondence from Bingham's investigations into her family's history (1980s); notebooks and journals; and other miscellaneous materials.
  - Writings, drafts, other materials (Box 1)
    - A Dangerous Personality (Box 1)
    - Wolf Hunt, Act 1, 2008 (Box 1)
    - Piggyback (Box 1)
    - Treason (7 folders) (Box 1)
    - Hopscotch (Box 1)
    - Wolfhunt, Charlie (Box 1)
    - Meet me in the Garden (Box 1)
    - The Truth about Growing Up Rich (Box 1)
    - Reflections in a Silver Spoon (Box 1)
    - Essays (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - A Rose for Madame Blavatsky (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - Libertinages (Box 1)
    - Short stories (Box 1)
    - Words in the Language (Box 1)
    - Nick of Time contract (Box 1)
    - Ideas for books and stories (Box 1)
  - Articles and reviews, 1960s-2000s (Box 1)
  - Transgressions (Box 1)
  - Straight Men (Box 1)
  - Small Victories (Box 1)
  - Sunstone Pier publisher (Box 1)
  - Transgressions-French publisher (Box 1)
  - Photocopied newspaper reviews (Box 2)
  - Family photographs and drawings, 1970s-2000s (Box 2)
  - 91st Street Garden, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Women Moving Millions, 2008-2009 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2008-2009 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Bingham School documents, 1800s? (Box 2)
  - Timothy Leary article (Box 2)
  - John Templeton address (Box 2)
  - Carrington blurb, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Family history and CIA research notes and files, 1980s (19 folders) (Box 2)
  - 7 notebooks and journals (Box 2)
- Accession (2010-0042), 1953-2010, 1 box
  Addition (2010-0042) (700 items; 1.5 lin. ft.; dated 1953-2010) includes writings and drafts, personal correspondence, communications with Sarabande, philanthropy correspondence, photograph albums, and videocassettes.
  - Videotapes (VHS) (Box 1)
    - Oreos with Attitude/Anemone Me, undated (Box 1)
    - Interview with Sallie Bingham, circa 1989 (Box 1)
    - Wolf Pen Branch Mill Farm, undated (Box 1)
    - Advance copy of Easy Six, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Sallie Bingham ballroom dancing video, 2000s (Box 1)
    - Acting Co. of Roanoke Valley Piggyback reading, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Photograph albums of ballroom dancing, travels, scenery, nature, undated (2 albums) (Box 1)
  - Book contracts, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
  - Copies of family letters (Box 1)
  - Philanthropy, 2008-2010 (Box 1)
  - Personal letters, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - Personal correspondence, 1989-2010 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2009-2010 (Box 1)
  - Sarabande Press (Box 1)
  - Wolf Pen Mill Farm (Box 1)
  - Women Writers workshop, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Professional letters, published works, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Writings and drafts, 1953-2009 (Box 1)
  - Kentucky Foundation for Women (Box 1)
  - Workshops, lectures, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Women Moving Millions charity (3 items) (Box 1)
  - Vortex Theatre, August 2009 (Box 1)
  - Bingham's high school yearbook, The Transcript, 1954 (Box 1)
- Accession (2010-0170), 1973-2010, 2 boxes
  Addition (2010-0170) (500 items; 0.8 lin. ft.; dated 1973-2010) includes personal journals and notebooks, printed materials with Bingham's published poems, correspondence (2009-2010), and some materials from Bingham's philanthropy and community activities.
  - 6 journals/notebooks, 2003-2010 (bulk 2007-2010) (Box 1)
  - Caperton, Bernard M. The Caperton Family, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Published works
    - The Monkey's Uncle, Epiphany, Winter/Spring 2009 (Box 1)
    - Oh Beautiful City of Dreams, Glimmer Train, No. 56, Fall 2005 (Box 1)
    - For B., In Praise, Toad, Daphne, and Worth, Threshold, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Personal correspondence, 2009-2010 (Box 1)
  - Drafts of writings
    - Telling Stories, first draft, 2009 (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Telling Stories, first draft, 2009 (Box 1)
    - Telling Stories, first drafts, 2009 (Box 2)
  - Tebot Bach contract materials, 2009 (Box 2)
  - Swan Day (Support Women Artists Now), 2009-2010 (Box 2)
  - Giving, 2009-2010 (Box 2)
  - Materials re: writing, 2010 (Box 2)
  - Crossing the Alps, 1989 (Box 2)
- Addition (2011-0064), 2009-2011 and undated, 1 box
  More than half of this addition consists of short story drafts and copies. Also included is correspondence, notes, photographs, and 4 compact discs.
  - Writings (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Anywhere You Send Me (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Bat (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Blackberry Winter (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - The Blue Box (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Boy in the Bathrobe (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Exchange (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Fifteen (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - If In Darkness (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Roquefixade (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Rough Air (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Stations of the Cross (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)
    - Stories for Sarah
      - Found (Box Acc. 11/064: Box 1)